CODING NINJAS

Sagar Khatri

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/sagarkhatri Github: https://github.com/devsagarkhatri dev.sagarkhatri@gmail.com 8765000808 Varanasi

SUMMARY

I am a hardworking and ambitious individual with a great passion for the Information Technology & Computer Science industry. I am currently in my second year of studying Master of Computer Applications at Madan Mohan Malaviya University of Technology. I am an articulate person, which enables me to effectively communicate with a wide range of people. I am seeing a full-time position in your company where I can put into practice my knowledge and experience, ultimately benefiting the operations of the organisation that I work for.

EDUCATION

Madan Mohan Malaviya University of Technology 2018 - 2021

Master of Computer Applications

CGPA/Aggregate: 7.44

Veer Bahadur Singh Purvanchal University 2014 2017

Bachelor of Computer Applications

CGPA/Aggregate: 73.91%

Sunbeam School Lahartara 2013 - 2014

Intermediate (CBSE Board) CGPA/Aggregate: **72.20%**

Sunbeam School Lahartara 2011 - 2012

High School

CGPA/Aggregate: 8.0

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Public Speaking, Java, OOPs, Data Structures, Python, Machine

Learning

EXPERIENCE

Coding Ninjas

July 2020 - Present

Teaching Assistant

My primary work here was to solve doubts raised by students. I had to understand their perspective to get where they are stuck in the questions. Apart from this, I had to mentor 5 students and encourage them to complete their exercises on time.

Indian Institute of Technology, Kanpur

June 2019 - July 2019

Classroom Training

Learnt the concepts of Machine Learning and the Basics of Convolutional Neural Network(CNN) under the Classroom Training on Artificial Intelligence in IIT Kanpur.

PROJECTS Diabetes Prediction

Used Supervised Machine Learning to create a model for the prediction of Diabetes based of the input features. The dataset used was "pima-indian-

diabetes.csv" from Kaggle.

Car Racing GUI Game

10 Days

Single player based Car Racing game built with Java using the concepts of Swing. The player here has 20 lives, in-case he hits the cars coming from the other side.

Scoring is done based on the distance traveled by the car on the road until his lives are exhausted.

It is enabled with storing player names and declaring the winner based on the MySql to record and store the database.

GUI Archery Game

16 Days

Single player based Archery game built with Java using the concepts of Swing. In the game, the player is provided with 12 arrows using which he has to hit the Bull's Eye to score.

Scoring is done based on the distance of the arrow from the center of the Bull's Eye.

It is enabled with storing player names and declaring the winner based on the MySql to record and store the database.

TicTacToe GUI Game

7 Days

Two player based TicTacToe game built with Java using the concepts of Swing. It was enabled with storing player names and declaring the winner based on the MySql to record and store the database.

CERTIFICATION

Interview Preparation | JAVA by Coding Ninjas

Verify: https://students.codingninjas.com/verify/8514224e69d98e81

Interview Preparation | Aptitude Rounds by Coding Ninjas

Verify: https://students.codingninjas.com/verify/cc7aa46ca7b4984d, https://students.codingninjas.com/verify/863c8def501e293b